♪The golden phoenix is flying in the colorful sky♪
♪ طائر الفينيق الذهبي يطير في السماء الملونة ♪
♪Such a rare and perfect match♪
♪ مثل هذه المباراة النادرة والمثالية
♪I won't be oppressed by the palace rules♪
♪ لن أكون مضطهدة بقواعد القصر ♪
♪Love and time are rarely aligned♪
نادرًا ما يتماشى الحب والوقت
♪But it's such a perfect match♪
♪ لكنها مباراة مثالية ♪
♪Long live the Queen? I prefer a sweet smile♪
♪ تحيا الملكة؟  انا افضل ابتسامة حلوة ♪
♪One is willing to tolerate while the other is willing to hit♪
واحد على استعداد للتسامح والآخر مستعد للضرب ♪
♪Bring it on, my rival♪
اجلبه على منافسي
♪No might can fly up to the sky♪
♪ لا يمكن أن يطير إلى السماء
♪It doesn't affect my elegance at all♪
♪ لا يؤثر على أناقتي إطلاقا
♪Great at writing family rules♪
رائع في كتابة قواعد الأسرة ♪
♪And bullying the imperial bodyguards♪
♪ والتنمر على حراس الإمبراطور ♪
♪When I turn around and flash my smile, tears will be shed♪
♪ عندما أستدير وأومض ابتسامتي ، ستذرف الدموع
♪I'm here to annoy you♪
♪ أنا هنا لأزعجك ♪
♪The Queen has arrived! Nothing is a big deal to me♪
وصلت الملكة!  لا شيء مهم بالنسبة لي ♪
♪Shouldering the responsibility as your virtuous and capable wife♪
تحمل المسئولية كزوجة فاضلة وقادرة
♪The Queen has arrived! She brings happiness to all♪
وصلت الملكة!  إنها تجلب السعادة للجميع
♪Just have fun in the world! I won't turn back♪
♪ فقط استمتع في العالم!  لن أعود ♪
♪What a perfect match♪
♪ يا لها من تطابق مثالي
[Adapted from Jinjiang Wenxuecheng's "Queen Liu Heipang", written by Ge Yang]
[مقتبس من "الملكة ليو هيبانغ" لجينجيانغ وينكسويتشنغ ، بقلم جي يانغ]
[The Legendary Life of Queen Lau]
[الحياة الأسطورية للملكة لاو]
[Episode 17]
[الحلقة 17]
[This work is fictitious. Any resemblance to reality is coincidental]
[هذا العمل وهمي.  أي تشابه مع الواقع هو من قبيل الصدفة]
Why is he not here yet?
لماذا هو ليس هنا بعد؟
Did he run into any danger on his way here?
هل واجه أي خطر وهو في طريقه إلى هنا؟
Why is His Majesty not here yet?
لماذا لم يتواجد جلالة الملك بعد؟
[His Majesty Must Win] Yes. I'm worried.
[يجب أن يفوز صاحب الجلالة] نعم.  انا قلق.
Why is he not here yet?
لماذا هو ليس هنا بعد؟
Where is he?
أين هو؟
Where?
أين؟
[His Majesty Must Win] Your Majesty!
[يجب أن يفوز جلالة الملك] جلالة الملك!
[Good luck, His Majesty] Good luck, Your Majesty!
[حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك] حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك!
Yunzhang is here.
Yunzhang هنا.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
Keep going!
واصل التقدم!
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
All the best, Yunzhang.
أتمنى لك كل خير ، Yunzhang.
All the best!
أتمنى لك كل خير!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
You haven't had breakfast. Have some porridge.
لم تتناول الفطور.  تناول بعض العصيدة.
You must be tired of running. Take a sip of water.
يجب أن تكون قد سئمت من الجري.  خذ رشفة من الماء.
Let me know if you're feeling unwell.
اسمحوا لي أن أعرف إذا كنت تشعر بتوعك.
I've brought medicines with me.
لقد أحضرت معي الأدوية.
Go away.
يبتعد.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
Good luck, Your Majesty.
حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
[Always Support His Majesty] Mother loves you, Your Majesty!
[ادعمي دائمًا جلالة الملك] الأم تحبك يا جلالة الملك!
Come on!
هيا!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Other women want to be in the same bed with His Majesty.
تريد نساء أخريات أن يكن في نفس السرير مع جلالة الملك.
Why are you dreaming about being Empress Dowager?
لماذا تحلم بأن تكون الإمبراطورة الأرملة؟
No, that's not it.
هذا ليس المقصود.
I would never dare think like that.
لن أجرؤ على التفكير بهذه الطريقة.
But you said, "Mother loves you."
لكنك قلت ، "الأم تحبك".
This...
هذه...
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It's just a mentality.
إنها مجرد عقلية.
For instance,
على سبيل المثال،
His Majesty ran a big lap and is drenched with sweat.
ركض جلالة الملك في حضن كبير وهو مبلل بالعرق.
We feel so worried about him.
نشعر بقلق شديد عليه.
It has been tough for the kid.
لقد كان صعبًا على الطفل.
Are there other groups?
هل هناك مجموعات أخرى؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Look over there.
انظري هناك.
Look at them.
انظر اليهم.
They are commonly known as suitors.
هم معروفون عادة بالخاطبين.
When they see His Majesty running,
عندما يرون جلالة الملك يجري ،
they're probably dreaming about marrying His Majesty.
ربما يحلمون بالزواج من جلالة الملك.
[His Majesty Must Win] They are your rivals.
[يجب أن يفوز صاحب الجلالة] إنهم خصومك.
I'm not one of them.
أنا لست واحدًا منهم.
Any more?
أي أكثر من ذلك؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Look at them.
انظر اليهم.
The ruler
الحاكم
of the country.
من البلاد.
Isn't he setting a bad example?
ألا يضرب مثالا سيئا؟
All they care about is His Majesty's nation.
كل ما يهتمون به هو أمة صاحب الجلالة.
They are the guardians.
هم الأوصياء.
Those who are wearing this outfit
أولئك الذين يرتدون هذا الزي
are the maidservants who used to serve the Late Emperor.
هم الخادمات الذين اعتادوا خدمة الإمبراطور الراحل.
They expect His Majesty to take care of them for the rest of their lives.
إنهم يتوقعون أن يعتني بهم جلالة الملك لبقية حياتهم.
Those stories are not exactly right.
هذه القصص ليست صحيحة تمامًا.
Not everyone is coveting the man's body.
لا يشتهي الجميع جسد الرجل.
What about you, Your Majesty?
ماذا عنك يا جلالة الملك؟
Me?
أنا؟
My father...
والدي...
All the best, Your Majesty.
كل التوفيق ، جلالة الملك.
[His Majesty Must Win] Your Majesty.
[يجب أن يفوز جلالة الملك] جلالة الملك.
His Majesty was looking at me.
كان جلالة الملك ينظر إلي.
He didn't.
لم يفعل.
He was looking at me.
كان ينظر لي.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Come on, Your Majesty.
تعال يا جلالة الملك.
Liu Xie.
ليو شيه.
Can we just let this go?
هل يمكننا ترك هذا يذهب؟
She's right, Grand Chancellor.
إنها على حق أيها المستشارة الكبرى.
He has been running for a long time.
لقد كان يركض لفترة طويلة.
I...
أنا...
I'm afraid that Zhang won't be able to take it.
أخشى أن تشانغ لن يكون قادرًا على أخذها.
He only ran half a lap.
ركض نصف لفة فقط.
What do you know?
ماذا تعرف؟
If Zhang fails to complete ten laps,
إذا فشل تشانغ في إكمال عشر لفات ،
they will despise him even more.
بل يزدرون عليه.
Stay out of this.
هذا لا يخصك.
I am the Queen.
انا الملكة.
Who else is going to help him if I don't?
من غيره سيساعده إذا لم أفعل؟
A man of honor always keeps his words.
رجل الشرف يحفظ كلماته دائما.
Have you not tortured Xuan enough?
هل لم تعذب شوان بما فيه الكفاية؟
Why do you have to take it so seriously?
لماذا عليك أن تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد؟
Send Her Majesty
أرسل جلالة الملك
back to the palace.
العودة إلى القصر.
Fine. Keep acting all arrogant.
بخير.  استمر في التصرف بغطرسة.
Mother said this.
قالت الأم هذا.
If you make a mistake and refuse to change it,
إذا أخطأت ورفضت تغييرها ،
I should do it on your behalf.
يجب أن أفعل ذلك نيابة عنك.
Lest you get punished by God.
لئلا يعاقب الله.
You...
أنت...
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
I'll stand up against you and make atonement for your sins.
سأقف ضدك وأكفر عن ذنوبك.
Good luck!
حظا طيبا وفقك الله!
All the best!
أتمنى لك كل خير!
All the best, Your Majesty.
كل التوفيق ، جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
All the best.
أتمنى لك كل خير.
Good luck, Your Majesty.
حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Her Majesty is here!
صاحبة الجلالة هنا!
I'm coming!
أنا قادم!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Here I come, Your Majesty.
لقد جئت إلى هنا يا جلالة الملك.
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Before I came to the palace,
قبل مجيئي إلى القصر ،
my mother told me to be a good wife and a good Queen.
قالت لي أمي أن أكون زوجة صالحة وملكة صالحة.
I'm here to show you my support.
أنا هنا لأظهر لك دعمي.
I won't allow anyone to mock you.
لن أسمح لأحد أن يسخر منك.
Is this how you're going to show your support?
هل هذه هي الطريقة التي ستظهر بها دعمك؟
According to the book,
وبحسب الكتاب ،
being frightened
الخوف
can unleash your potential.
يمكن أن يطلق العنان لإمكاناتك.
Although the Empress Dowager
على الرغم من أن الإمبراطورة الأرملة
and my father look down on you,
وأبي ينظر إليك بازدراء ،
I believe in you.
إنني أ ثق بك.
Wangcai.
وانجكاي.
Run, Your Majesty!
اركض يا صاحب الجلالة!
Come on, Your Majesty.
تعال يا جلالة الملك.
Run fast, Your Majesty.
اركض بسرعة يا جلالة الملك.
That's Liu Xie's daughter.
هذه ابنة ليو شيه.
I'm still very confused
ما زلت في حيرة من أمري
about whether Her Majesty
حول ما إذا كانت صاحبة الجلالة
is on our side.
في صالحنا.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I thought she was going to share His Majesty's joy and sorrow.
اعتقدت أنها ستشارك جلالته الفرح والحزن.
Look what she's doing now.
انظر ماذا تفعل الآن.
His Majesty is scared of dogs. What should we do now?
جلالة الملك خائف من الكلاب.  ماذا يجب أن نفعل الآن؟
Look.
نظرة.
Look at how fit Their Majesties are.
انظر إلى مدى لياقة أصحاب الجلالة.
They are the perfect representations of the strong Donghao Empire.
إنها التمثيلات المثالية لإمبراطورية Donghao القوية.
I believe
أعتقد
under Their Majesties' leadership,
تحت قيادة أصحاب الجلالة ،
we will soon welcome a brand-new future.
سنرحب قريبًا بمستقبل جديد تمامًا.
Run, Your Majesty.
اركض يا صاحب الجلالة.
Run!
يجري!
[His Majesty is the Best]
[صاحب الجلالة هو الأفضل]
[Taihe Hall]
[تايهي هول]
Liu Baiyu.
ليو بايو.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Did you write this note?
هل كتبت هذه المذكرة؟
What note?
ما المذكرة؟
I don't know what you're talking about.
لا أعرف ما الذي تتحدث عنه.
You don't?
لم تكن؟
Why are you here, then?
لماذا انت هنا اذن؟
Do I need to tell you why I'm here?
هل علي أن أخبرك لماذا أنا هنا؟
Stop acting dumb.
توقف عن التصرف الغبي.
You forged my writing,
لقد زورت كتاباتي ،
right?
الصحيح؟
What nonsense is that? Do you have proof?
ما هذا الهراء؟  هل لديك دليل؟
Proof?
دليل - إثبات؟
Do you want proof?
هل تريد برهان؟
[Fight Enemy with Enemy] To be honest,
[حارب العدو مع العدو] لأكون صادقًا ،
although my handwriting is not that pretty,
على الرغم من أن خط يدي ليس بهذه الروعة ،
it is my signature.
إنه توقيعي.
It's not something you can forge just like that.
إنه ليس شيئًا يمكنك تزويره بهذا الشكل.
You call writing wrong words your signature, huh?
أنت تسمي كتابة كلمات خاطئة توقيعك ، أليس كذلك؟
What's wrong with writing the wrong words?
ما الخطأ في كتابة الكلمات الخاطئة؟
It can be my signature too.
يمكن أن يكون توقيعي أيضا.
You might be able to imitate my handwriting,
قد تكون قادرًا على تقليد خط يدي ،
but can you imitate my personality?
لكن هل يمكنك تقليد شخصيتي؟
I know.
أنا أعرف.
You helped me with my studies,
لقد ساعدتني في دراستي ،
so that you could learn my handwriting.
حتى تتمكن من تعلم خط يدي.
You wanted to frame Yunzhang
أردت تأطير Yunzhang
at important times like this, right?
في أوقات مهمة كهذه ، أليس كذلك؟
You say what you want.
انت تقول ما تريد.
I didn't do anything like that.
لم أفعل أي شيء من هذا القبيل.
Are you still trying to defend yourself?
هل مازلت تحاول الدفاع عن نفسك؟
Fengyue has told me everything.
لقد أخبرني Fengyue بكل شيء.
Do you think you can deceive me
هل تعتقد أنك تستطيع أن تخدعني
by bringing up Fengyue's name?
بإحضار اسم Fengyue؟
Deceive?
يخدع؟
Do I have to deceive you?
هل علي أن أخدعك؟
Fengyue has already come clean about what you did
لقد أدرك Fengyue بالفعل ما فعلته
in front of your father and everyone else.
امام والدك والجميع.
I'm just here to give you a heads-up.
أنا هنا فقط لأقدم لك تنبيهًا.
Your father will be right here.
سيكون والدك هنا.
This...
هذه...
Father?
أب؟
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
Fengyue said this.
قال Fengyue هذا.
You eavesdropped on our conversation
لقد تنصتت على حديثنا
and decided to meet one trick with another.
وقررت مواجهة خدعة بأخرى.
You forged my handwriting to frame Yunzhang.
لقد زورت خط يدي لتأطير Yunzhang.
Fengyue also said
قال Fengyue أيضا
that you put in a lot of effort
أنك بذلت الكثير من الجهد
to imitate my handwriting.
لتقليد خط يدي.
You stayed up for nights just to learn how to imitate my handwriting,
سهرت الليالي لتتعلم تقليد خط يدي
and you barely succeed.
وبالكاد تنجح.
How ridiculous.
كم هذا سخيف.
Your handwriting looks just like a kid's handwriting.
يبدو خط يدك تمامًا مثل خط يد طفل.
Do I need to spend days and nights learning how to imitate this?
هل أحتاج لقضاء أيام وليال في تعلم تقليد هذا؟
Tell you what.
اخبرك بماذا.
It only took me less than an hour
استغرق الأمر مني أقل من ساعة فقط
to master it.
لإتقانها.
Liu Baiyu.
ليو بايو.
So who's being ridiculous now?
إذن من هو السخيف الآن؟
You finally admitted it.
لقد اعترفت بذلك أخيرًا.
You wrote this note, didn't you?
لقد كتبت هذه المذكرة ، أليس كذلك؟
No...
رقم...
That's not what I meant.
ليس هذا ما قصدته.
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
Come with me now.
تعال معي الان.
I want everyone to know
اريد ان يعرف الجميع
what you did.
ماذا فعلت.
Let me go.
دعني اذهب.
This is not up to you.
هذا ليس متروك لك.
Come with me now.
تعال معي الان.
No.
رقم.
♪I'm searching in the large forest♪
♪ أنا أبحث في الغابة الكبيرة ♪
♪For a lasting and joyful relationship♪
لعلاقة دائمة وممتعة
♪It is said that husband and wife are birds of the same forest♪
يقال إن الزوج والزوجة طيور من نفس الغابة
♪But each flies at the sight of great disasters♪
لكن كل واحد منهم يطير على مرأى من الكوارث الكبرى
♪I fly over the palace walls♪
أطير فوق جدران القصر ♪
♪And envy the smiling pairs on the peach blossom branches♪
وحسد الأزواج المبتسمة على أغصان زهر الخوخ
♪I've traveled the world and seen so much♪
♪ لقد سافرت حول العالم ورأيت الكثير ♪
♪That I know how good you are♪
♪ أنني أعرف كم أنت جيد ♪
♪I will follow you as you fly♪
سأتبعك وأنت تطير ♪
I can't do this any longer.
لا يمكنني فعل هذا بعد الآن.
I can't.
لا أستطبع.
I can't run anymore. Just go ahead without me.
لا أستطيع الركض بعد الآن.  فقط تفضل بدوني.
♪Flying in pairs♪
♪ تحلق في أزواج ♪
♪Becoming a pair of birds in the same forest♪
♪ اصبح زوج من الطيور في نفس الغابة ♪
Jinfeng.
جينفنغ.
When your father was reprimanding me today,
عندما كان والدك يوبخني اليوم
for the first time,
لأول مرة،
I thought what he said made sense.
اعتقدت أن ما قاله منطقي.
After I heard what he said,
بعد أن سمعت ما قاله ،
I started doubting myself.
بدأت أشك في نفسي.
♪Love goes on♪
الحب يستمر ♪
However, you said something
ومع ذلك ، قلت شيئا
and I regained my confidence again.
واستعدت ثقتي مرة أخرى.
♪Becoming a pair of birds in the same forest♪
♪ اصبح زوج من الطيور في نفس الغابة ♪
You said you believed that I would be a good Emperor.
قلت إنك تؤمن بأني سأكون إمبراطورًا جيدًا.
I...
أنا...
♪I'll stay with you♪
♪ سأبقى معك ♪
♪We won't be separated♪
♪ لن نفترق ♪
Did you hear that?
هل سمعت هذا؟
Husband and wife are one.
الزوج والزوجة واحد.
Get up.
استيقظ.
It doesn't mean we have to run together.
هذا لا يعني أننا يجب أن نركض معًا.
It's going to end really soon.
سينتهي قريبًا حقًا.
Are you really going to give up now?
هل حقا ستستسلم الآن؟
Can't you tell
لا يمكنك ان تقول
that I really want to give up?
التي أريد حقا أن أتخلى عنها؟
Then, why did you decide to run with me?
إذن ، لماذا قررت أن تركض معي؟
♪We won't be separated♪
♪ لن نفترق ♪
We're husband and wife.
نحن زوج وزوجة.
I can't leave you alone.
لا أستطيع تركك بمفردك.
Really?
هل حقا؟
Then, why are you sitting here?
إذن ، لماذا أنت جالس هنا؟
I told you I couldn't run anymore.
أخبرتك أنني لا أستطيع الركض بعد الآن.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Husband and wife are one.
الزوج والزوجة واحد.
You can't run anymore,
لا يمكنك الجري بعد الآن ،
so I'll do it for you.
لذلك سأفعل ذلك من أجلك.
♪You came into my heart♪
أتيت إلى قلبي ♪
♪And brought me into your dream♪
وأتت بي إلى حلمك ♪
♪Although separated♪
على الرغم من الانفصال ♪
♪You're always there in the twists and turns♪
♪ أنت دائمًا موجود في المنعطفات والمنعطفات
♪Your dimples♪
♪ غمازاتك ♪
♪Remind me of something♪
♪ ذكرني بشيء ♪
♪Who can explain the poem to me?♪
من يستطيع أن يشرح لي القصيدة؟
♪Suddenly you light up with a smile♪
♪ فجأة تضيء بابتسامة
♪Another page full of poems♪
♪ صفحة أخرى مليئة بالقصائد ♪
♪What an exuberant vernal scene♪
يا له من مشهد ربيعي غزير ♪
♪If you are sincere and earnest♪
إذا كنت مخلصًا وجادًا ♪
♪Keep it going year after year♪
♪ استمر في العمل عاماً بعد عام
♪I will fall for you when you show up♪
♪ سوف أقع في حبك عندما تظهر ♪
Mother.
الأم.
♪Suddenly your smiling face♪
♪ فجأة وجهك المبتسم
All the best, Your Majesty!
كل التوفيق ، جلالة الملك!
♪Becomes unforgettable for me♪
♪ اصبحت لا تنسى بالنسبة لي ♪
Your Majesty, come on!
جلالة الملك ، تعال!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Come on!
هيا!
♪My love for you is getting deeper and deeper♪
حبي لك يزداد عمقا واعمق
♪I'm still greedy even in my dreams♪
♪ ما زلت جشعًا حتى في أحلامي ♪
Come on, Your Majesty.
تعال يا جلالة الملك.
Come on!
هيا!
Grand Chancellor.
المستشار الأكبر.
Look.
نظرة.
He ran the laps and received the punishment.
ركض الأحضان ونال العقوبة.
After all, Zhang is the ruler of the country.
بعد كل شيء ، تشانغ هو حاكم البلاد.
There's no need to press on, right?
ليس هناك حاجة للضغط ، أليس كذلك؟
Jinfeng is really something too.
Jinfeng شيء حقًا أيضًا.
She has been running for so long, but she is still not tired yet.
لقد ظلت تعمل لفترة طويلة ، لكنها لا تزال غير متعبة بعد.
Don't you worry about her?
ألا تقلق عليها؟
Even I am worried about her.
حتى أنا قلقة عليها.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Look at them.
انظر اليهم.
The husband and the wife are working hand in hand.
الزوج والزوجة يعملان يدا بيد.
Isn't that nice?
أليس هذا لطيفا؟
♪Who can explain the poem to me?♪
من يستطيع أن يشرح لي القصيدة؟
Good luck, Your Majesty.
حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Keep going.
واصل التقدم.
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
Come on!
هيا!
Come on, Your Majesty!
تعال يا جلالة الملك!
Liu Baiyu.
ليو بايو.
Look at what you've done.
انظر إلى ما قمت به.
Look at the hardship you put Yunzhang and my sister-in-law through.
انظر إلى المصاعب التي وضعتها في Yunzhang وزوجة أخي.
Come on!
هيا!
They...
أنهم...
You call this a hardship?
هل تسمي هذا مشقة؟
Why are you so mean?
لماذا أنت لئيم؟
What else do you want them to do?
ماذا تريد منهم أن يفعلوا أيضًا؟
Anyway, this is not what I imagined.
على أي حال ، ليس هذا ما تخيلته.
It's not supposed to end up like this.
ليس من المفترض أن ينتهي الأمر بهذا الشكل.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Come on, Your Majesty.
تعال يا جلالة الملك.
Good luck!
حظا طيبا وفقك الله!
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
Keep going!
واصل التقدم!
I found the culprit.
لقد وجدت الجاني.
Let her go.
اسمح لها أن تذهب.
Baiyu?
بايو؟
What did my daughter do?
ماذا فعلت ابنتي؟
Why is she the culprit?
لماذا هي الجاني؟
The note
المذكرة
was written by Liu Baiyu, your daughter.
كتبته ابنتك ليو بايو.
She was the only one who had ever helped me with my studies.
كانت هي الوحيدة التي ساعدتني في دراستي.
She knows how my handwriting looks.
هي تعرف كيف تبدو خط يدي.
I think
أظن
no one in the imperial capital
لا أحد في العاصمة الإمبراطورية
can imitate my handwriting as well as she does.
يمكنها تقليد خط يدي كما تفعل.
Is it really you?
هل هو انت حقا
I only wanted to help His Majesty pass the exam.
أردت فقط مساعدة جلالة الملك في اجتياز الامتحان.
I didn't expect to cause him so much trouble.
لم أتوقع أن يسبب له الكثير من المتاعب.
Father, I was wrong.
أبي ، لقد كنت مخطئا.
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Keep going!
واصل التقدم!
Baiyu.
بايو.
You have let me down.
لقد خذلتني
I...
أنا...
You...
أنت...
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
Keep going!
واصل التقدم!
Come on, Your Majesty.
تعال يا جلالة الملك.
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
They have all left.
لقد غادروا جميعا.
Are you still going to keep up the act?
هل مازلت ستستمر في العمل؟
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
I'm talking to you.
أنا أتحدث إليكم.
Can you hear me?
أيمكنك سماعي؟
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
It's all your fault.
هذا كله خطأك.
I'm sure Father hates me now.
أنا متأكد من أن أبي يكرهني الآن.
-You did this to yourself. -It's all your fault.
-أنت فعلت ذلك لنفسك.  - هذا كله خطأك.
Why are you saying as if I was the one who made the mistake?
لماذا تقول كأنني أنا من أخطأ؟
It's all your fault.
هذا كله خطأك.
Your fault.
خطأك.
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
Zhang. Zhang.
تشانغ. تشانغ.
We found the truth of the cheating case.
وجدنا حقيقة قضية الغش.
You can stop running now.
يمكنك التوقف عن الجري الآن.
I always keep my words.
أنا دائما أحتفظ بكلماتي.
I'll finish all ten laps.
سأنهي كل اللفات العشر.
Can you still run?
لا يزال بإمكانك الجري؟
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
لا تقلق يا جلالة الملك.
We'll definitely complete the laps.
بالتأكيد سنكمل الدورات.
Jinfeng...
جينفنغ ...
Your Majesty, you don't have to compliment me.
يا صاحب الجلالة ، ليس عليك أن تمدحني.
I know I did a good job, right?
أعلم أنني قمت بعمل جيد ، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, you did.
نعم أنت فعلت.
But...
ولكن...
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
لا تقلق يا جلالة الملك.
We'll see you at the finishing line.
سنراك عند خط النهاية.
Let's go, Yunzhang.
دعنا نذهب ، Yunzhang.
Come on, Yunzhang.
تعال ، Yunzhang.
Why won't you give up?
لماذا لا تستسلم؟
We've done so much.
لقد فعلنا الكثير.
Giving up now means we're admitting our defeat.
الاستسلام الآن يعني أننا نعترف بهزيمتنا.
However, I learned something today too.
ومع ذلك ، تعلمت شيئًا اليوم أيضًا.
What?
ماذا؟
I think
أظن
you prefer me over your father.
تفضلني على والدك.
Did you just learn about this today?
هل علمت للتو عن هذا اليوم؟
You're not that smart after all.
أنت لست بهذه الذكاء بعد كل شيء.
We can overcome all difficulties being together.
يمكننا التغلب على جميع الصعوبات التي نعيشها معًا.
Go!
يذهب!
(His Majesty)
(جلالته)
(is running toward the finishing line)
(يجري نحو خط النهاية)
(with Her Majesty on his back.)
(مع صاحبة الجلالة على ظهره).
Will His Majesty succeed?
هل ينجح جلالة الملك؟
Can he do this?
هل يستطيع فعل هذا؟
(We all have faith in His Majesty, right?)
(كلنا نؤمن بجلالة الملك ، أليس كذلك؟)
(His Majesty's fans, show me your hands!)
(يا جماهير جلالة الملك ، أرني يديك!)
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
(Let's cheer him on!)
(دعونا نشجعه!)
Keep going, Your Majesty.
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة.
[Lingshu Academy] Come on!
[أكاديمية Lingshu] تعال!
Keep going!
واصل التقدم!
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
(He represents)
(يمثل)
(the history of Donghao Empire.)
(تاريخ إمبراطورية Donghao.)
(He's not fighting alone.)
(إنه لا يقاتل وحده.)
(He's not alone!)
(إنه ليس وحده!)
♪It is said that husband and wife are birds of the same forest♪
يقال إن الزوج والزوجة طيور من نفس الغابة
♪But each flies at the sight of great disasters♪
لكن كل واحد منهم يطير على مرأى من الكوارث الكبرى
♪I fly over the palace walls♪
أطير فوق جدران القصر ♪
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
♪I've traveled the world and seen so much♪
♪ لقد سافرت حول العالم ورأيت الكثير ♪
♪That I know how good you are♪
♪ أنني أعرف كم أنت جيد ♪
Why aren't they here yet?
لماذا لم يتواجدوا هنا بعد؟
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
♪Flying in pairs♪
♪ تحلق في أزواج ♪
♪Becoming a pair of birds in the same forest♪
♪ اصبح زوج من الطيور في نفس الغابة ♪
♪That is sweeter than lovebirds and richer than gold♪
هذا أحلى من طيور الحب وأغنى من الذهب
Keep going!
واصل التقدم!
-Keep going, Your Majesty! -He's here!
-استمر يا جلالة الملك!  -هو هنا!
He's here!
إنه هنا!
♪Love goes on♪
الحب يستمر ♪
Come on, Your Majesty!
تعال يا جلالة الملك!
Come on.
هيا.
Keep going, Yunzhang.
استمر ، Yunzhang.
Hang in there, Yunzhang.
شنق هناك ، Yunzhang.
Yunzhang, keep going!
Yunzhang ، استمر!
♪Spring is beautiful even when there are difficulties♪
♪ الربيع جميل حتى عند وجود صعوبات ♪
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Come on, Your Majesty.
تعال يا جلالة الملك.
Keep going, Yunzhang.
استمر ، Yunzhang.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Keep going.
واصل التقدم.
You're almost at the finishing line. Keep going!
أنت على وشك الانتهاء.  واصل التقدم!
Keep going, Your Majesty!
استمر يا صاحب الجلالة!
Hang in there, Your Majesty!
انتظر هناك ، جلالة الملك!
Come on!
هيا!
We're here.
نحن هنا.
Run!
يجري!
Come on!
هيا!
♪I fly over the palace walls♪
أطير فوق جدران القصر ♪
♪And envy the smiling pairs on the peach blossom branches♪
وحسد الأزواج المبتسمة على أغصان زهر الخوخ
♪I've traveled the world and seen so much♪
♪ لقد سافرت حول العالم ورأيت الكثير ♪
♪That I know how good you are♪
♪ أنني أعرف كم أنت جيد ♪
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
You're amazing!
أنت مدهش!
♪And stay with you when you don't♪
♪ وابق معك عندما لا تفعل
His Majesty is too amazing!
جلالة الملك مدهش للغاية!
♪Flying in pairs♪
♪ تحلق في أزواج ♪
♪Becoming a pair of birds in the same forest♪
♪ اصبح زوج من الطيور في نفس الغابة ♪
♪That is sweeter than lovebirds and richer than gold♪
هذا أحلى من طيور الحب وأغنى من الذهب
♪Until a hundred years old♪
♪ حتى مائة عام ♪
We won!
فزنا!
♪Still in pairs♪
♪ لا يزال في أزواج ♪
♪Love goes on♪
الحب يستمر ♪
♪Flying in pairs♪
♪ تحلق في أزواج ♪
♪A pair of birds in the same forest♪
♪ زوج من الطيور في نفس الغابة ♪
♪Spring is beautiful even when there are difficulties♪
♪ الربيع جميل حتى عند وجود صعوبات ♪
♪If you don't fly♪
♪ إذا لم تطير ♪
♪I'll stay with you♪
♪ سأبقى معك ♪
♪We won't be separated♪
♪ لن نفترق ♪
♪Flying in pairs♪
♪ تحلق في أزواج ♪
I never expected
لم أتوقع أبدا
Jinfeng
جينفنغ
to be such a loyal woman.
أن تكوني امرأة مخلصة.
The more I look at her,
كلما نظرت إليها أكثر ،
the more I like her.
كلما أحببتها أكثر.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It's the nation's honor
إنه شرف الأمة
to have their Emperor and Queen living in harmony.
أن يعيش الإمبراطور والملكة في وئام.
♪Spring is beautiful even when there are difficulties♪
♪ الربيع جميل حتى عند وجود صعوبات ♪
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
I can now rest assured.
يمكنني الآن أن أطمئن.
♪We won't be separated♪
♪ لن نفترق ♪
[Good luck, Your Majesty]
[حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك]
Good job.
أحسنت.
Let me ask you something.
اسمح لي أن أسألك سؤالا.
There are as many stars here
هناك العديد من النجوم هنا
as there are in Xianpa Village.
كما هو الحال في قرية Xianpa.
Didn't I tell you this before?
ألم أخبرك بهذا من قبل؟
You're looking at the same stars.
أنت تنظر إلى نفس النجوم.
Why do I feel like they are different?
لماذا أشعر أنهم مختلفون؟
Perhaps
ربما
it's the companion that makes it different.
الرفيق هو الذي يجعل الأمر مختلفًا.
You said you wanted to ask me a question.
قلت أنك تريد أن تسألني سؤالاً.
Why did you
لماذا فعلت
help me?
ساعدني؟
Aren't we rivals?
ألسنا منافسين؟
We're not only rivals,
نحن لسنا منافسين فقط ،
but we're also friends.
لكننا أيضًا أصدقاء.
It's a win-win situation.
انه وضع فوز.
You wanted to be the Zhuangyuan,
أردت أن تكون Zhuangyuan ،
and I didn't want to get the last place.
ولم أرغب في الحصول على المركز الأخير.
There's no conflict between these two.
لا يوجد تعارض بين هذين.
That makes sense.
منطقي.
Why did we take the bet so seriously?
لماذا أخذنا الرهان على محمل الجد؟
We look so foolish.
نحن نبدو في غاية الحماقة.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Is there any other reason?
هل هناك أي سبب آخر؟
Also,
ايضا،
you look good.
تبدو بخير.
It's true.
انها حقيقة.
You really look good.
أنت حقا تبدو جيدا.
You haven't seen how all the maidservants went crazy over you
لم ترَ كيف جن جنون كل الخادمات عليك
when you were running today.
عندما كنت تجري اليوم.
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحا.
I have another question for you.
لدي سؤال اخر لك.
Why do you have so many questions?
لماذا لديك الكثير من الأسئلة؟
What did you add
ماذا أضفت
to the candle the other day?
إلى الشمعة في ذلك اليوم؟
Why did I fall asleep so soundly?
لماذا نمت بهدوء؟
About that...
عن ذلك...
Give me a proper answer.
أعطني إجابة مناسبة.
You look really tense on normal days.
تبدو متوترًا حقًا في الأيام العادية.
I wanted you to have a good rest.
أردت أن تحصل على قسط جيد من الراحة.
It was a remedy we did back home.
لقد كان علاجًا فعلناه في الوطن.
What remedy is that? It works so well.
ما علاج هذا؟  إنه يعمل بشكل جيد.
We grew up very poor.
لقد نشأنا فقراء جدا.
When we were kids,
عندما كنا أطفال،
our mothers used to go out to work.
اعتادت أمهاتنا على الخروج للعمل.
Those kids were especially pitiful
كان هؤلاء الأطفال يرثى لهم بشكل خاص
without their mothers around.
دون وجود أمهاتهم.
Some kids wouldn't stop crying.
لن يتوقف بعض الأطفال عن البكاء.
The doctors in the village
الأطباء في القرية
invented this remedy.
اخترع هذا العلاج.
When you burn the Mirror Moon Sand,
عندما تحرق مرآة قمر الرمال ،
it will release a scent similar to their mothers'.
ستطلق رائحة شبيهة برائحة أمهاتهم.
That's why the kids could sleep soundly.
هذا هو السبب في أن الأطفال يمكن أن يناموا بهدوء.
The scent of mothers.
رائحة الأمهات.
Why? Are you missing your mother?
لماذا ا؟  هل تفتقد والدتك؟
No, I'm not.
لا أنا لست كذلك.
I think
أظن
Mirror Moon Sand is a pretty elegant name.
Mirror Moon Sand هو اسم أنيق للغاية.
Are you too shy to admit that you miss your mother?
هل أنت خجول جدا للاعتراف أنك تفتقد والدتك؟
I miss my mother a lot.
افتقد والدتي كثيرا.
I miss the red braised pork my mother cooked.
أفتقد لحم الخنزير المطهو ​​ببطء الذي طهته والدتي.
Beef stew.
يخنة لحم البقر.
Cabbage and lamb.
ملفوف ولحم ضأن.
What a glutton.
يا لها من شره.
It's a taste I can only get from my mother.
إنه طعم لا يمكنني الحصول عليه إلا من والدتي.
I don't remember
أنا لا أتذكر
what my mom's food tasted like.
كيف تذوق طعام أمي.
Let's not talk about this anymore.
دعنا لا نتحدث عن هذا بعد الآن.
You haven't told me
أنت لم تخبرني
what Mirror Moon Sand actually is.
ما هو ميرور مون ساند في الواقع.
I worry that it might upset you.
أخشى أن ذلك قد يزعجك.
Don't worry. Just tell me the truth.
لا تقلق.  فقط قل لي الحقيقة.
I have run around the imperial city ten times.
لقد ركضت حول المدينة الإمبراطورية عشر مرات.
Do you think I will get upset by this?
هل تعتقد أنني سأغضب من هذا؟
Tell me the truth.
أخبرني الحقيقة.
Mirror Moon Sand is made with the earth in the mountains
مرآة القمر الرمل مصنوعة من الأرض في الجبال
and the droppings of 30 different insects.
وفضلات 30 حشرة مختلفة.
Droppings?
ذرق؟
That's all.
هذا كل شئ.
You can take your time to digest the information.
يمكنك أن تأخذ وقتك في استيعاب المعلومات.
Sufang, let's go.
سوفانغ ، دعنا نذهب.
Sufang.
سوفانغ.
Sufang, let's go home.
سوفانغ ، دعنا نذهب إلى المنزل.
Mothers smell like droppings.
رائحة الأمهات مثل الفضلات.
Is she kidding me?
هل هي تمزح معي؟
That's quite interesting.
هذا مثير جدا للاهتمام.
-Help! -Stand right there.
-مساعدة!  - قف هناك.
-Stop running. -Help!
-توقف عن الركض.  -مساعدة!
Help!
مساعدة!
Stop running.
توقف عن الركض.
You have nowhere to run now.
ليس لديك مكان لتركض فيه الآن.
Do you know who I am?
هل تعرف من أكون؟
We have no idea who you are,
ليس لدينا فكرة من أنت ،
but it's not like we care.
لكن الأمر ليس كما لو كنا نهتم.
We only care about money.
نحن نهتم فقط بالمال.
-Give it to me. -Don't touch me.
-اعطني اياه.  -لا تلمسني.
Let it go!
دعها تذهب!
Give it to me.
اعطني اياه.
Let go!
اتركه!
Get your hands off her.
ابعد يديك عنها
Who are you?
من أنت؟
It doesn't matter who I am.
لا يهم من أنا.
Brat.
شقي.
Do you have a death wish?
هل لديك رغبة في الموت؟
Attack!
هجوم!
Mister.
سيد.
Thank you so much.
شكراً جزيلاً.
You're welcome.
على الرحب والسعة.
I'm here
أنا هنا
to save you.
لإنقاذك.
What's your name, mister?
ما اسمك يا سيد؟
It doesn't matter what my name is.
لا يهم ما اسمي.
I'll see you under the peach tree.
أراك تحت شجرة الخوخ.
What's his name?
ما أسمه؟
Why is he not here yet?
لماذا هو ليس هنا بعد؟
Young Lady.
إمرأة شابة.
Come home with us.
تعال إلى المنزل معنا.
The groom has waited an entire day for you
لقد انتظر العريس يومًا كاملاً من أجلك
in the bridal room.
في غرفة الزفاف.
No.
رقم.
I won't come with you.
لن آتي معك.
I'll stay here and wait for my mister.
سأبقى هنا وانتظر سيدتي.
You don't even know the mister's name.
أنت لا تعرف حتى اسم السيد.
He definitely won't return.
بالتأكيد لن يعود.
I'll wait for him
سأنتظره
even if it means I have to wait here forever.
حتى لو كان ذلك يعني أنني يجب أن أنتظر هنا إلى الأبد.
You don't need to wait here forever.
لا تحتاج إلى الانتظار هنا إلى الأبد.
Have you always been on the tree?
هل كنت دائما على الشجرة؟
Yes, I have.
نعم لدي.
How long have you been there?
كم بقيت هنالك؟
Since forever.
منذ ذلك الحين إلى الأبد.
Mister.
سيد.
You are fated to be mine.
أنت مقدر أن تكون لي.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Mister!
سيد!
Mister.
سيد.
Nearly there.
كدنا نصل.
Miss.
يغيب.
Miss, where did you go?
انسة اين ذهبت؟
Don't go, Miss.
لا تذهب يا آنسة.
No.
رقم.
I won't marry him.
لن أتزوجه.
I have someone in my heart.
لدي شخص ما في قلبي.
-Young Lady. -I won't marry him.
-إمرأة شابة.  - لن أتزوجه.
Young Lady.
إمرأة شابة.
I won't.
أنا لن.
Please. Let me go.
لو سمحت.  دعني اذهب.
I won't marry him.
لن أتزوجه.
Young Lady.
إمرأة شابة.
Mister.
سيد.
It's you.
انه انت.
[Double Happiness]
[سعادة مزدوجة]
[The Search for Love]
[البحث عن الحب]
Why didn't he write any stories about their married life?
لماذا لم يكتب أي قصص عن حياتهم الزوجية؟
We're done reading the first part,
انتهينا من قراءة الجزء الأول ،
and the second part is not released yet.
والجزء الثاني لم يصدر بعد.
I hope the author didn't give up on this story.
آمل ألا يتخلى المؤلف عن هذه القصة.
Such a good story.
هذه قصة جيدة.
Why did you only share this with me now?
لماذا تشارك هذا معي الآن فقط؟
Sister-in-law, you have really great taste.
أخت الزوج ، لديك ذوق رائع حقًا.
I shared this book with others,
شاركت هذا الكتاب مع آخرين ،
and they called me uncultured.
ودعوني غير مثقف.
What do they know?
ماذا يعرفون؟
This is a good novel.
هذه رواية جيدة.
Why does the Mister look so handsome?
لماذا يبدو السيد وسيم جدا؟
I wonder what his name is.
أتساءل ما هو اسمه.
Perhaps...
ربما...
He's too handsome.
إنه وسيم للغاية.
He's the most handsome man I've ever seen.
إنه أكثر رجل وسيم رأيته في حياتي.
That's enough.
هذا يكفي.
I'll buy one for each of you when the second book is released.
سأشتري واحدة لكل واحد منكم عند إصدار الكتاب الثاني.
Your Majesty is the best.
جلالة الملك هو الأفضل.
You're the best.
أنت الأفضل.
Look.
نظرة.
They're coming in our direction.
إنهم يأتون في اتجاهنا.
They're too handsome.
إنهم وسيمون جدا.
So handsome.
وسيم جدا.
Why does Yunzhang
لماذا Yunzhang
look different today?
تبدو مختلفة اليوم؟
Why are they so handsome?
لماذا هم وسيمون جدا؟
Where are they going?
إلى أين هم ذاهبون؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Why are you still reading here?
لماذا ما زلت تقرأ هنا؟
Where did they go?
أين ذهبوا؟
They went to Yufang Garden.
ذهبوا إلى حديقة يوفانغ.
Why did they go to Yufang Garden?
لماذا ذهبوا إلى حديقة يوفانغ؟
The examination result will be released today.
سيتم الإعلان عن نتيجة الفحص اليوم.
They're waiting for the results at the Yufang Garden.
إنهم ينتظرون النتائج في حديقة يوفانغ.
Are you not going to check your results?
ألن تقوم بفحص نتائجك؟
Oh, right.
صحيح.
[His Majesty is the Best, His Majesty Must Win]
[جلالة الملك هو الأفضل ، جلالة الملك يجب أن يفوز]
[Good Luck, Her Majesty]
[حظا سعيدا يا جلالة الملك]
[Results]
[نتائج]
Good luck, Your Majesty.
حظا سعيدا جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
From now on,
من الان فصاعدا،
Liu Xie won't be able to act this arrogant again.
لن يتمكن Liu Xie من التصرف بهذه المتغطرسة مرة أخرى.
Look at how spirited His Majesty is.
انظر إلى مدى روح جلالة الملك.
I'm sure His Majesty will win.
أنا متأكد من أن جلالة الملك سيفوز.
I've planned a celebratory night.
لقد خططت لأمسية احتفالية.
The only thing we need now is the results.
الشيء الوحيد الذي نحتاجه الآن هو النتائج.
Grand Tutor Wei has arrived.
لقد وصل Grand Tutor Wei.
Look at Old Man Wei's face.
انظر إلى وجه العجوز وي.
Why is he pulling a long face?
لماذا يشد وجهه الطويل؟
He looks more upset than he was last year.
يبدو مستاء أكثر مما كان عليه العام الماضي.
Not just that.
ليس ذلك فحسب.
He looks more upset than two years ago.
يبدو مستاء أكثر مما كان عليه قبل عامين.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Do you want to reveal the results yourself?
هل تريد الكشف عن النتائج بنفسك؟
Why is he smiling at me?
لماذا يبتسم لي؟
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
Are you in the last place again?
هل انت في المكان الاخير مرة اخرى؟
I'm feeling a little nervous.
أشعر بقليل من التوتر.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
We'll do what we always do.
سنفعل ما نفعله دائمًا.
Do what we always do?
افعل ما نفعله دائما؟
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
[Results]
[نتائج]
[The First Class]
[الدرجة الأولى]
[The Top Three will be titled]
[ستتم تسمية المراكز الثلاثة الأولى بعنوان]
[Duan Yunzhang]
[دوان يون تشانج]
[First Place, Duan Yunzhang] Congratulations to His Majesty
[المركز الأول ، دوان يون تشانج] مبروك لجلالة الملك
for winning the Zhuangyuan title.
[المركز الأول ، Duan Yunzhang] لفوزه بلقب Zhuangyuan.
I did it!
أنا فعلت هذا!
His Majesty is going to govern the country.
جلالة الملك سيحكم البلاد.
His Majesty is really going to govern the country.
جلالة الملك سيحكم البلاد حقًا.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
His Majesty won first place.
فاز جلالة الملك بالمركز الأول.
Does it mean that you lost the bet?
هل هذا يعني أنك خسرت الرهان؟
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحا.
I won't lose as long as I'm not in the last place.
لن أخسر طالما أنني لست في المركز الأخير.
What if you get the last place?
ماذا لو حصلت على آخر مكان؟
It no longer matters
لم يعد الأمر مهمًا
as long as he has the reins now.
ما دام مقاليده الآن.
♪Long live the Queen?♪
♪ تحيا الملكة؟
♪I prefer a sweet smile♪
♪ افضل الابتسامة الحلوة ♪
♪One is willing to tolerate while the other is willing to hit♪
واحد على استعداد للتسامح والآخر مستعد للضرب ♪
♪Bring it on, my rival♪
اجلبه على منافسي
♪No might can fly up to the sky♪
♪ لا يمكن أن يطير إلى السماء
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Are you that happy that His Majesty is going to govern the country?
هل أنت سعيد لأن جلالة الملك سيحكم البلاد؟
Am I happy?
هل انا سعيد؟
Are you not?
ألست كذلك؟
In Xianpa Village, this is what we call sorrow.
في قرية Xianpa ، هذا ما نسميه الحزن.
Then how does a happy face look?
إذن كيف يبدو الوجه السعيد؟
♪The Queen has arrived!♪
وصلت الملكة!
This is a happy face.
هذا وجه سعيد.
♪Nothing is a big deal to me♪
♪ لا شيء يمثل مشكلة كبيرة بالنسبة لي
♪Shouldering the responsibility♪
تحمل المسؤولية ♪
♪As your virtuous and capable wife♪
كزوجة فاضلة وقادرة ♪
I'm so sad, Sufang.
أنا حزين جدا ، سوفانج.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
♪She brings happiness to all♪
إنها تجلب السعادة للجميع
♪Just have fun in the world!♪
♪ فقط استمتع في العالم!
♪I won't turn back♪
♪ لن أعود ♪
♪What a perfect match♪
♪ يا لها من تطابق مثالي
[Liu Jinfeng, Yu Changya]
[ليو جينفنغ ، يو تشانجيا]
Sister-in-law.
أخت الزوج أو اخت الزوجة.
Do you know what your result is?
هل تعرف ما هي نتيجتك؟
Haven't you seen my sad face?
ألم ترى وجهي الحزين؟
It's fine, Yunyan.
لا بأس ، يونيان.
There's always a winner and the lower.
هناك دائما فائز وأدنى.
I'm fine with getting the last place.
أنا بخير في الحصول على المركز الأخير.
No.
رقم.
You didn't get the last place.
لم تحصل على آخر مكان.
There's a place that comes after the last?
هل هناك مكان يأتي بعد الأخير؟
No. You got the second last place.
لا ، لقد حصلت على المركز الثاني الأخير.
So who gets the last place?
إذن من حصل على المركز الأخير؟
How should I
كيف استطيع
deal with the Grand Chancellor?
التعامل مع المستشار الكبير؟
I think you should break his legs first,
أعتقد أنه يجب عليك كسر ساقيه أولاً ،
so that he can stop walking into my sight.
حتى يتمكن من التوقف عن السير في عيني.
What's the use of breaking his legs?
ما فائدة كسر رجليه؟
We should slap him in the face.
يجب أن نصفعه على وجهه.
That old man
هذا الرجل العجوز
thinks he's better than everyone else
يعتقد أنه أفضل من أي شخص آخر
just because he's good-looking.
فقط لأنه حسن المظهر.
How childish.
كيف طفولية.
He has a strong physique.
يتمتع بلياقة بدنية قوية.
Why don't we just beat him up?
لماذا لا نضربه فقط؟
We have to be quick.
علينا أن نكون سريعين.
How reckless.
كم هو طائش.
That's too impulsive.
هذا مندفع للغاية.
I don't want to make things so difficult for him.
لا أريد أن أصعب الأمور عليه.
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Do it.
افعلها.
Do it!
افعلها!
Bite it.
عضه.
Bite it now.
عضه الآن.
I won!
انا ربحت!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Can you do something serious?
هل يمكنك فعل شيء جاد؟
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
You're going to govern the country soon.
ستحكم البلاد قريبًا.
You'll have plenty of time in the future
سيكون لديك متسع من الوقت في المستقبل
to deal with serious matters.
للتعامل مع الأمور الخطيرة.
We should enjoy ourselves now.
يجب أن نتمتع بأنفسنا الآن.
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
Yes.
نعم.
Bite it.
عضه.
Go.
يذهب.
It's so stupid.
هذا غبي جدا.
Keep going.
واصل التقدم.
If you don't want to talk about serious matters,
إذا كنت لا تريد التحدث عن الأمور الجادة ،
let's talk about something else.
لنتحدث عن شيء آخر.
I know when to punish and when to reward someone.
أعرف متى أعاقب ومتى أكافئ شخصًا ما.
Besides, I didn't get this result
علاوة على ذلك ، لم أحصل على هذه النتيجة
all by myself.
كل شئ بمجهودى الشخصى.
So...
لذا...
You know
أنت تعرف
that I'm not very good with my words.
أني لست جيدًا بكلماتي.
I'm thinking of getting you guys
أفكر في الحصول على يا رفاق
something special.
شئ مميز.
-Thanks, Your Majesty. -Thanks, Yunzhang.
-شكرا جلالة الملك.  -شكرا Yunzhang.
Look at this jade pendant.
انظر إلى قلادة اليشم هذه.
His Majesty obviously custom-made this just for me.
من الواضح أن جلالة الملك صنع هذا خصيصًا من أجلي.
I know His Majesty loves me the most.
أعلم أن جلالة الملك يحبني أكثر.
How shameless.
كيف وقح.
Look at the pattern.
انظر إلى النمط.
This is obviously good stuff.
من الواضح أن هذه أشياء جيدة.
I didn't know His Majesty loves me this much.
لم أكن أعرف أن جلالة الملك يحبني كثيرًا.
That's nothing compared to mine.
هذا لا شيء مقارنة بي.
Look at my blood jade pendants.
انظر إلى قلادات اليشم الدموي.
They come in a pair.
يأتون في زوج.
This is the blood relationship Yunzhang and I share.
هذه هي علاقة الدم التي نشارك فيها مع Yunzhang.
The love between us
الحب بيننا
is incomparable.
لا يضاهى.
Thanks, Yunzhang.
شكرا Yunzhang.
Thanks, Your Majesty.
شكرا جلالة الملك.
We'll go and have fun.
سنذهب ونستمتع.
We'll get going.
سوف نبدأ.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
-Thanks, Your Majesty.
-شكرا جلالة الملك.  -شكرا جلالة الملك.
Go ahead.
إنطلق.
Fine.
بخير.
It's been half a day
لقد مر نصف يوم
and he's still missing.
وما زال مفقودًا.
How ungrateful.
كيف جاحد.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Am I doing it right?
أفعل ذلك الحق؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Pink and purple,
زهري وبنفسجي،
which one do you think is better?
أي واحدة أفضل برأيك؟
Pink.
لون القرنفل.
Should I make a bow knot or a flower knot?
هل يجب أن أصنع عقدة فيونكة أم زهرة؟
Bow knot.
عقدة القوس.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Sufang.
سوفانغ.
Can you stop talking to me?
هل يمكنك التوقف عن التحدث معي؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It wasn't me.
لم يكن أنا.
He's here.
إنه هنا.
He's here?
هل هو هنا؟
I opened the door this morning
فتحت الباب هذا الصباح
and found this brocade box at the doorstep.
ووجدت صندوق الديباج هذا عند عتبة الباب.
Look at the color and the craftsmanship.
انظر إلى اللون والحرفية.
The fragrance too.
العطر أيضا.
I'm sure His Majesty sent this here.
أنا متأكد من أن جلالة الملك أرسل هذا هنا.
(That's why he kept me waiting.)
(لهذا السبب جعلني أنتظر).
(He was preparing a gift for me.)
(كان يعد لي هدية).
It's just a boring box.
إنه مجرد صندوق ممل.
Why are you making a fuss out of it?
لماذا تثير ضجة للخروج منه؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Why don't you open it?
لماذا لا تفتحه
[I'll see you under the peach tree.]
[سأراك تحت شجرة الخوخ.]
(I'll see you)
(سوف أراك)
(under the peach tree.)
(تحت شجرة الخوخ).
That's so cheesy.
هذا جبني جدا.
What a cliche.
يا لها من مبتذلة.
It's so romantic that he wants to meet under the peach tree.
إنه رومانسي للغاية لدرجة أنه يريد أن يلتقي تحت شجرة الخوخ.
(It's just like what happened in the book.)
(إنه تمامًا مثل ما حدث في الكتاب).
(Let's just follow the plot.)
(دعنا فقط نتبع الحبكة.)
It's fine. You can get up now.
لا بأس.  يمكنك الاستيقاظ الآن.
Let's move on to the next chapter.
دعنا ننتقل إلى الفصل التالي.
Attack.
هجوم.
Tie her up.
ربط لها حتى.
This...
هذه...
This is not part of the story, right?
هذا ليس جزء من القصة ، أليس كذلك؟
You got it wrong.
لقد فهمت خطأ.
Not the next chapter.
ليس الفصل التالي.
You should do the next scene.
يجب أن تفعل المشهد التالي.
Young Lady.
إمرأة شابة.
I won't come with you.
لن آتي معك.
I'm waiting for...
أنا أنتظر...
I'm here.
أنا هنا.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Of course, it's me.
بالطبع هذا أنا.
Who else were you expecting?
من غيرك كنت تتوقع؟
That's enough. You're dismissed.
هذا يكفي.  تم رفضك.
Thanks, Imperial Physician Yu.
شكرا للطبيب الإمبراطوري يو.
So you've been hiding in the tree?
إذن كنت مختبئًا في الشجرة؟
How long have you been up there?
منذ متى وانت هناك؟
Since...
حيث...
Shut it.
أغلقه.
I don't want to listen to it said by you.
لا أريد الاستماع إلى ما قلته.
Why did you tie me up?
لماذا ربطتني؟
I'm afraid that you might forget our bet.
أخشى أنك قد تنسى رهاننا.
I'm here to remind you of that.
أنا هنا لتذكيرك بذلك.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Don't come near me.
لا تقترب مني.
Are you going to break your promise?
هل ستنتهي بوعدك؟
Of course, I am.
بالطبع أنا.
Who wants this to be done to them?
من يريد أن يفعل هذا لهم؟
Fine.
بخير.
I like you for who you are.
أنا معجب بك لما أنت عليه.
So can I not do this?
لذا لا يمكنني فعل هذا؟
Of course...
بالطبع...
not.
ليس.
You didn't win the bet fairly either.
أنت لم تفز بالرهان أيضًا.
Yunyan told me
قال لي يونيان
that you submitted an empty paper deliberately.
أنك قدمت ورقة فارغة عمدا.
Of course, I did that on purpose.
بالطبع ، لقد فعلت ذلك عن قصد.
With my standard,
بمعياري ،
I can easily win the top three places.
يمكنني بسهولة الفوز بالمراكز الثلاثة الأولى.
So you...
وانت ايضا...
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I won't do anything
لن أفعل أي شيء
to your charming face
على وجهك الساحر
before I have a proper plan.
قبل أن يكون لدي خطة مناسبة.
The tools I imported from Persia
الأدوات التي استوردتها من بلاد فارس
will arrive three days later.
سيصل بعد ثلاثة أيام.
When they arrive,
متى يصلون،
it'll be the best time to do the surgery.
سيكون أفضل وقت لإجراء الجراحة.
Yu Changya.
يو تشانجيا.
Jinfeng.
جينفنغ.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
You are fated to be mine.
أنت مقدر أن تكون لي.
You...
أنت...
♪Only second to the Emperor♪
♪ في المرتبة الثانية بعد الإمبراطور ♪
♪Anyone who's against it should back off♪
♪ أي شخص ضدها يجب أن يتراجع
♪I'll make a face and fear no heaven and earth♪
♪ سأصنع وجهًا ولا أخاف السماء والأرض
♪I'll let you go for now♪
♪ سأتركك تذهب الآن ♪
♪I'm not a motherly model♪
♪ أنا لست عارضة أزياء
♪Nor am I the most beautiful lady♪
♪ ولست أجمل سيدة
♪Who says those of humble origin can't be elegant?♪
♪ من يقول أن من هم من أصول متواضعة لا يمكن أن يكونوا أنيقين؟
♪Bring it on. Let's make a big bet♪
اجلبه.  لنقم برهان كبير ♪
♪To be a huge winner♪
♪ أن تكون فائزًا كبيرًا
♪A couple of quarrelsome lovers♪
♪ زوجان من العشاق المشاكسين
♪An odd coincidence became a much-told tale♪
أصبحت مصادفة غريبة حكاية يكثر الحديث عنها
♪Holding bad cards yet I play well still♪
♪ أحمل بطاقات سيئة ولكني ألعب بشكل جيد ♪
♪Accept the plot twist♪
♪ اقبل تطور الحبكة ♪
♪Cut all the romantic themes♪
♪ قص كل المواضيع الرومانسية ♪
♪To talk about love is childish♪
الحديث عن الحب طفولي ♪
♪I shall redefine peerless elegance♪
♪ سأعيد تعريف الأناقة منقطعة النظير
♪Are you ready?♪
♪ هل أنت جاهز؟
♪Tremble, my rivals♪
ارتجف يا منافسي
♪Look, the phoenix in the sky is actually a little crow♪
♪ انظر ، طائر الفينيق في السماء هو في الواقع غراب صغير
♪Surprising the world with its talent♪
يفاجئ العالم بموهبته
♪Experiencing the ups and downs♪
♪ تجربة الصعود والهبوط ♪
♪In return for a wiser life♪
مقابل حياة أكثر حكمة ♪
♪Don't ever look down on the little crow♪
♪ لا تنظر أبدًا إلى الغراب الصغير
♪She wears the crown and controls the world♪
ترتدي التاج وتتحكم في العالم
♪Striking back♪
♪ الرد ♪
♪To be the head of the harem♪
أن يكون رأس الحريم ♪
♪Look, the phoenix in the sky is actually a little crow♪
♪ انظر ، طائر الفينيق في السماء هو في الواقع غراب صغير
♪Surprising the world with its talent♪
يفاجئ العالم بموهبته
♪Experiencing the ups and downs♪
♪ تجربة الصعود والهبوط ♪
♪In return for a wiser life♪
مقابل حياة أكثر حكمة ♪
♪Don't ever look down on the little crow♪
♪ لا تنظر أبدًا إلى الغراب الصغير
♪She wears the crown and controls the world♪
ترتدي التاج وتتحكم في العالم
♪Striking back♪
♪ الرد ♪
♪To be the head of the harem♪
أن يكون رأس الحريم ♪
♪Little crow♪
♪ غراب صغير ♪
♪Dear little crow♪
♪ عزيزي الغراب الصغير ♪
♪Striking back to be the head of the harem♪
الضرب على رأس الحريم
♪Little crow♪
♪ غراب صغير ♪
[Adapted from Jinjiang Wenxuecheng's "Queen Liu Heipang", written by Ge Yang]
[مقتبس من "الملكة ليو هيبانغ" لجينجيانغ وينكسويتشنغ ، بقلم جي يانغ]